Guide to the Walter Stainton papers, 1914-1983
Stainton, Walter papers, 1914-1983
- Series XI. Assorted Newspaper and Magazine Articles
  - Film Articles
    - Newspaper Articles About Propaganda in Films (Box 10, Folder 100)
    - Notes and Articles About Sound Films, 1950s, 1950s (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - "The Movies Come to Syracuse," from "New York History," Vol. 36, 1955, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "Occupancy Fire Record: Motion Picture Theatres," 1956, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "Film Projectors at the N.Y. Fair," 1964, June 17, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper Articles on Film, December 1963-July 1964, December 1963-July 1964 (Box 13, Folder 68)
    - Assorted Newspaper Articles, Most from Ithaca Journal (Box 13, Folder 69)
    - Assorted Newspaper Articles (Box 13, Folder 70)
    - "I.Q. Famous Lines. Who Said Which?" (Box 13, Folder 86)
    - Photograph of actors and actresses enacting scenes for "The Lottery Man" - includes a write up from the Ithaca Journal September 28-29, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 87)
  - Theatre Articles
    - Assorted Theatre Newspaper Articles (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Theatre Articles by Francis Hodge, 1959, December 1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "The Meaning of 'Macbeth,'" by Louis Marsh (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Facsimile of 'Typical Elizabethan Plays,' 3rd Edition (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "A Summary of the Theater Season," 1949, Mat 29, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "One Act Plays for Little Theatre Groups", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - "A Listing of Original Plays Produced by Members of National Theater Conference," 1947-1948, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "Theatre Focus" and Related Notes, Fall 1979, Fall 1979 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Aldwych Theatre World Theatre Seasons, 1968, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Assorted Newspaper Clippings Concerning Drama (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - "State of New York Article 124 - State Theatre Act" February 21, 1950, February 21, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - "Administration of College Dramatics," by Virgil A. Anderson, from 'The Quarterly Journal of Speech" XXII No.1 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Theatre Newsletter and Papers on "Pattern of Use of Theatre" (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Booklets on Theatre Writing (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - "Theatre Audiences Today" (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - "A Course of Lectures on Dramatic Art and Literature," By Augustus William Schlegel, 1946, 1846 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - "Killing off the Theater," Walter Kerr, April 1955, April 1955 (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - Two Articles by Mordecai Gorelik, These include: "The Scenic Imagination" and "I am the Einstein of the New Stage Form..." (Box 10, Folder 87)
    - Assorted Articles on Theatre and Teaching (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - "The Theatre and the Playhouse" (Box 10, Folder 92)
    - Assorted Publications on Stage Writing (Box 10, Folder 93)
    - "New York's Obsolete Theatres," by Howard S. Cullman, from the "New York Herald Tribune", 1949, March 13, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Articles About Art and Women in Theatre Lighting, 1950-1951, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - "Old Theatres for New," by Michael Dewell, 1963, February 1963 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Assorted Theatre Articles (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - "The American Theater," by Arthur Miller, 1955, January 1955 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - Assorted Newspaper Cut-outs, 1950s (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Assorted Newspaper Clippings Concerning Theatre, 1950s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Newspaper Articles About Theatre Buildings, 1935-1953, 1935-1953 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - "Actors Just Act-Or No 'Pear-Shaped Tones,' by Cornelia Otis Skinner, December 1942, December 12, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - "The Cliche Expert Testifies on the Drama," October 1951, October 6, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 63)
    - Assorted Theatre and Film Articles (Box 12, Folder 68)
  - Assorted Articles (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Newspaper and Magazine Articles, 19371-1954, 1937-1954; One Article from 1947 Concerning Stainton. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "A Remote Control Dimmer," by Ralph E. Armington and Harry A. Atwater, 1940, May 4, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Article About Stainton's Commission as Captain in the Army, 1942, October 7, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Articles About Octogan Club's "Joan of Arkansas," 1951, May 1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "The Boy Scout" #1 and 8, 1911, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Assorted Programs and Piece on "Baker Maps" (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1947-1953, 1947-1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1954-1955, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ithaca "50 Years Ago" Articles, Pub. 1941-1942, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Assorted Articles Concerning Alumni, Theatre, and N.Y., 1933 -1979, 1933-1976 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Paper to Electrical Contractors from T. Fuchs at Wyoming Valley Pageant, July 1928, July 1928 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - World's Fair Article, 1939, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Life Magazine Article on New Plastic Lens, February 14, 1949, February 14, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Cover and Table of Contents for "Illuminating Engineering," May 1943, May 1943 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Cornell Alumni News, July 1959, July 1959 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - List of Jobs Built by Westinghouse Electric Corporation at Windsor MFG and Repair Corp. (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Articles Concerning Death of Shirley Goldner in Montreal Fire, July 1956, July 1956 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Assorted Newspaper Articles, Includes interview with Ethel Barrymore (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Front Page of the Ithaca Journal, June 13, 1959, June 13, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Newspaper Articles Relating to Cornell Dramatic Club (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Newspaper Articles Relating to Cornell Dramatic Club, Reprint of Cornell Daily Sun from February 5, 1909 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - "An Exhibition of Cinematographic Apparatus," Edited by Carl Fredrik Nelson, 1957, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Articles on World War II, 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Pages About Various Artistic Mediums from "Time," 1930, June 13, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Assorted Magazine Articles (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Assorted Articles on Propaganda (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - New York Herald Tribune, February 15, 1942, February 15, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Various Newspaper Articles, 1950s, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Newspaper Articles About Vaudeville (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - "The Repertory of Arts, Manufactures, and Agriculture," Second Series, 1825, April 1825 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Papers on Jean A. LeRoy, French Photographer, 1930s, 1930s (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Optics and Modern Painting," by Dr. Rogers D. Rusk, "Scientific Monthly," May 1934, May 1934 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Profile on Bassett Jones, "New Yorker," 1939, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "The History of Dioramas," from "The Museum News" Vol. 17, 1940, February 15, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Works About Robert Flaherty, 1943-1964, 1943-1964 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Record of Magazine Articles, 1946-1964, 1946-1964 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - "Image, Journal of Photography of George Eastman House," Vol. IV, No. 7, 1955, October 1955 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - "Kleig Light," from the "New Yorker," 1957, July 13, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Profile on Abe H. Feder from the "New Yorker," 1960, October 22, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "The General Auditorium" by James Hull Miller, from "American Institute of Architects Journal," 1960, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "America's Most Complete Human Document," by Cleveland Amory, 1962, August 25, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - "The 1893 Duryea Automobile," by Don H. Berkebile, 1964, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - "Catalogue Number Eight," from "Motley Books," 1966, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Profile on Jason Buchter, from the "New Yorker" (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Articles About Louis Jacques Mande Daguerre (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Assorted Articles on Panoramas (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Chapter from Text, "An Avalanche of Attacks," by George Eastman (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Assorted Newspaper Articles, 1940s, 1940s (Box 15, Folder 32)
- Series XII. Assorted Publications
  - "Home and Highway," August 1953, August 1953 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - "Wisconsin Stage," Summer 1956, Summer 1956 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - "Today's Filmmaker," June 1974, June 1974 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - "AFI Education Newsletter," January-February, 1982, January-February, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - "The Movie Home Journal," June 1926, June 1926 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - "The Playgoer,"1930, "The Playgoer," 1930 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - "Players Incorporated" Magazine, 10th Anniversary (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Roxy Theatre Weekly Review and Playbill/Articles for "Big Time," 1927 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - "News From Home," Theatre Issue, February-March 1949, March 1949; Special attention is paid in this issue to theater fires. (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - "The Collection of Regional History and University Archives," May 1971, May 1971 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Rule No.36 "State Standard Building Code for Places of Public Assembly," April 6, 1957, April 6, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - "The Art of Rehearsal," by George Bernard Shaw, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Book on Les Festivals de Montreal, 1936-1956, 1936-1956 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Assorted Pamphlets and Newsletters, 1947-1952, 1947-1952 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Report of the President: Cornell University, 1958-1959, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Book for the Stratford Festival, 1965, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Handbook of the Women;s Self Government Association at Cornell University (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Music and Lyrics for "Norma," Inspired by Norma Talmadge, Lyrics by Sidney Mitchell and Music by Archie Gottler. (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Booklet About the Speaker's Coach in the House of Commons (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - "Presenting the Past: An Informal Guide to Planning Your Town's Historical Celebrations," 1970s, 1970, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - The Museum of Modern Art Department of Film Circulating Programs, 1973, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - "Modern Maturity," Publication of the American Association of Retired Persons, June-July 1975, June-July 1975 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Arts and Sciences Vol. I No. I, 1980, February 1980 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Report of the President, Cornell University, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - "Origins of the Cornell University Library Associates," by Walter J. Mueller, 1986, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - "The Covered Wagon," 1923, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - "Harper's Magazine," 1938-1941, 1938-1941; Includes: "Do you Know Aaron Slick?" and "Why Do You Fear Me, Nellie?" (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Booklet About Willard Straight Hall, 1947, September 1947 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - "Home and Highway," 1953, Spring 1953; Includes: "Mark Twain's River," an article about showboats. (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - "Saturday Review," 1959, December 19, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - "Aeta Projects Progress Newsletter," Volume IV, No.2, 1960, November 1960 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - "Imagery Magazine," Volume I, Number 1, 1961, Winter 1961 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - "The British Film Industry Quarterly Gazette," 1961-1963, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - "The Journal of the Society for Film History Research," Volume II, Number 11, June 1966, June 1966 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Assorted Papers and Publications Concerning Frank Capra (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Assorted Brochures and Packets (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - "Cosmopolitan" Issue with Cornell Articles (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - "The College of Arts and Sciences, Cornell" Magazine (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Booklet on D.W. Griffith's "The Birth of a Nation," 1955, January 1955 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - "Time" Magazine, 1946, June 3, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "The Scientific Monthly," October 1951, October 1951 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "Time" Magazine, Vol. 59, No. 8, 1952, February 25, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "Das Filmgesich: Emil Jannings, 1928, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - "Festival de Cannes," March 1954, March 1954 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Stratford Shakespearean Festival (Canada) Pamphlets and Papers, 1961-1965, 1961-1965 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - American Shakespeare Festival Theatre and Academy, November 1964, November 27, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - "The Civilization of Llhuros," 1972, 1972; Exhibition organized by the Andrew Dickson White Museum of Art (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Assorted Film and Theatre Brochures (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Assorted Pamphlets for Shakespearean Productions (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Festival of Contemporary American Arts at Cornell, June 1945, June 1945 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - "Futures in American Theatres" 1963, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 64)
  - "The Saturday Review," February 22, 1964, February 22, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 65)
  - Ithaca's "The Town Crier," August 1963/November 1964, August 8, 1963/November 12, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 66)
  - "The New York Theatre Market VS The New York Market" (Box 12, Folder 67)
  - Various Booklets for Film Institutes and Societies, 1939-1955, 1939-1955 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - British Film Institute Documents, 1947-1956, 1947-1956 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - British Film Institute Documents, 1949-1965, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - American Museum of Photography, Early History (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - "Broadside: Theatre Library Association," December 1966, December 1966 (Box 13, Folder 78)
  - "The Weather Vein," Vol. 6, No. 3, 1926, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Gilbert Miller Presents: Max Reinhardt New York Repertory Season, 1927-1928, 1927-1928 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Shakespeare Memorial Theatre, A Season of Shakespearean Comedy, Stratford, 1960, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 41)
- Series XIII. Miscellaneous
  - Papers About Performance of Angna Enters" (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Pennsylvania Intercollegiate Dramatic Association (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Conference on Motion Picture Education, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Papers from Society of Cinematologists Meeting at University of Minnesota, March 19, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Sixth Annual Robert Flaherty Seminar, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Invitations and Event Programs, 1952-1959, 1952-1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photo Negatives of Cornell Library Hall (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Expense Sheets for Showing Films (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Master Painters as Source Material for Theatrical Productions" (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Collection of Theatre and Film Related Flyers (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Book for Edward Rose's "The Rosary," June 28, 1915, June 28, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Articles and Correspondence About Telegraphone, 1925-1949, 1924-1949 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Christmas Productions Photos, December 1925, December 1925 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Photos of Telegraphone, 1929, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Notebook, Pamphlets, Schematics, and Notes on Telegraphone, 1930, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Denishawn Dancers (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Film Programmes: "The Wonderland of Big Game," and "The Sign on the Door" (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Short Story About a Young Rat (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Advertisement for Cary Grant's "Indiscreet" and Anita Page Head Shot (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Happy New Year Drawings, Recent Paints by Agna Enters, 1951, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Programme of the Summer Film School Organized by the British Film Institute and Scottish Film Council, 1952, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - The Society for Film History Research, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Schwabe + Co. (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - R. W. Paul at Queen's Hall, 1896, 1896 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - "Mathematics-t he Subtle Fine Art," Professor James B. Shaw, November 1935, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - "A Survey Emphasizing Social Implications and Educational Use," by P. Freund, 1946, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 61)
  - Photo of Construction Workers from New York Herald Tribune, October 1932, October 2, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 74)
  - Festival of Contemporary American Arts at Cornell, June 19456 +, June 1945 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - "The Answer was No," by Jeanne Carruthers; Tribute to Dr. L. Bruce Carruthers on His Death in November 1957, November 1957 (Box 13, Folder 76)
  - The Telegraphone as Developed by Stainton (Photos0, 1928-1929, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Unnamed Portraits, 1884-1899, 1884-1899; One has the name T.M. Hutchinson on the back. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Assorted Unnamed Portraits, 1896-1909, 1896-1909; One picture is labeled Ellen I. Varley (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Wings Over Europe, 1938, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Postcards from the "Observer Film Exhibition," 1956, 1956; One has the name T.M. Hutchinson on the back. (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - "Speech Monographs," November 1949-August 1956, November 1949-August 1956 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Key to Photomontage by David Evans for "The Observer Film Exhibition," 1956, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Goodwin-Short Excerpts, Books, and Reference Works (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Drawing, Mirror Image of a Photograph of Famous Actors From "The Observer Film Exhibition" (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Goodwin-Short Excerpts, Books, and Reference Works (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Outline for Discussion on UMT (Box 15, Folder 41)